Finding Aid for the Richard P. Wunder Research Files, 1945-1989 MS.02
The Frick Collection/Frick Art Reference Library Archives
- Series V: Architectural Drawings, 1958-1975, 4.0 Linear feet (8 boxes)
  - The Architect's Eye
    - Catalog, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 4)
      Includes annotated published version and a galley.
    - Promotional materials, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 5)
      Press releases and newspaper clippings.
  - Architectural and Ornament Drawings
    Richard Wunder was commissioned to write the catalog,Architectural and Ornament Drawings of the 16th to the Early 19th Centuries in the Collection of University of Michigan Museum of Art. The catalog describes and illustrates 107 drawings acquired by the Museum during the late 1950s and early 1960s.
    - Correspondence, 1961-1966 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Notes and reviews, circa 1965 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Catalog (published), 1965 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Catalog (draft), 1964 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Catalog descriptions 1- 107 (drafts), circa 1964 (Box 55, Folder 1-5)
      Contains photographs, correspondence, notes, and drafts.
  - Italian Architecture Drawings
    Materials relate to the Summary Catalogue of Drawings by Identified Italian Architects in the Cooper Union Museum, which Wunder wrote during his time there.
    - Photographs, undated (Box 55, Folder 6-7)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1964 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Catalog, 1964 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Architectural, Ornament, Landscape and Figure Drawings
    Relates to the exhibition and catalog,Architectural, Ornament, Landscape and Figure Drawings collected by Richard Wunder. Mr. Wunder's personal collection was exhibited at Middlebury College in 1975.
    - Catalog, 1975 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - #1, Unknown Italian (Parma) -Doorway (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - #2, Challe -Architectural Fantasy (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - #3, Lassurance -Elevation of the Chateau de Petitbourg (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - #4, J.F. Blondel -Palace Facade (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - #5, M.D. Poppelmann -Palace Elevation (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - #6a, G. Jarmorini -Wall Altar (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - #6b, G. Jarmorini -Elevation of a Portal and Balcony (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - #6c, G. Jarmorini -Elevation of a Doorcase (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - #7, Buonfigani -Public Monument (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - #8, Unknown North Italian -Facade of a Church (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - #9, Passalacqua -Rospigliosi Altar (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - #10, Basoli -Papal Throne (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - #11, Unknown Italian -Wall Altar (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - #12, F. Minozzi -St. Bibiaba Altar (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - #13, Unknown Neapolitan -Church Decoration (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - #14, L. Arinelli -Catafalque (Box 56, Folder 19)
    - #15, Unknown Italian -Altarpiece Surround (Box 56, Folder 20)
    - #16, M. Tesi -Head, Altar (Box 56, Folder 21)
    - #17, Unknown Italian -Wall Decoration (Box 56, Folder 22)
    - #18, Mitelli -Doorcase with Herm (Box 56, Folder 23)
    - #19, Simoni -Capital (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - #20, Minozi -Catafalque Designs (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - #21, Bibiena -City Square (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - #22, Felice Giani -Two Monuments (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - #23, M. Tesi -Catafalque Monument (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - #24, Minozzi -Tomb Monument (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - #25, Bibiena -Stage Set (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - #26, Bibiena -Stage Set (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - #27, Sandoni -Stage Set, Hall and Sketches (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - #28, M. Tesi -Tents (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - #29, P. Fancelli -Stage Set (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - #30, Juvara -Architectural Fantasies (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - #31, Juvarra -Set for Teodosio il Giovane (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - #32, H. Robert -Arcade Statue of Marcus Aurelius (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - #33, H. Robert -Arcade, Stairs in Rear (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - #34, Cherpitel -Voltaire Procession (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - #35, Panini -Interior of Sistine Chapel (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - #36, Tavarone -Tromp L'oeil Decoration (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - #37, Mitelli -Tromp L'oeil Wall Decoration (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - #38, Unknown Italian -Tromp L'oeil Wall Decoration (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - #39, Mitelli -Illusionistic Wall Painting (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - #40, P. Panfili -Proscenium Arch (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - #41, M. Tesi -Garden Arcade (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - #42, Jarmorini -Ceiling Decoration (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - #43, Antonio and Giuseppe Rolli -Ceiling of Palace Marescotti (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - #44, G. Civoli -Ceiling Cove and Sketches (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - #45, P. Panfili -Ceiling Cove (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - #46a, F. Minozzi -Ceiling Section (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - #46b, F. Minozzi -Ceiling Section (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - #47, Vincenzo Brenna -Lunette (Bacchus) (Box 58, Folder 14)
    - #48, V. Brenna -Lunette (Apollo) (Box 58, Folder 15)
    - #49, Flamingo Minozzi -Arabesque Panel (Box 58, Folder 16)
    - #50, P. Panfili -Oval Frame (Box 58, Folder 17)
    - #51, Mitelli -Chapel of S. Maria dei Servi Bologna (Box 58, Folder 18)
    - #52, P. Panfili -Arch (Box 58, Folder 19)
    - #53, Mitelli -Rollwork Ornamentation (Box 58, Folder 20)
    - #54, Mitelli -Architectural Sketches (Box 58, Folder 21)
    - #55, Unknown Italian -Two Stage Wings (Box 58, Folder 22)
    - #56, Gandolpi -Design for an Inkstand (Box 58, Folder 23)
    - #57, Mitelli -Ceiling or Cupola Decorations (Box 58, Folder 24)
    - #58, Mitelli -Wall Painting Details (Box 58, Folder 25)
    - #59, Mitelli -Ornamental Details (Box 58, Folder 26)
    - #60, Mitelli -Ceiling Painting Details (Box 58, Folder 27)
    - #61, F. Minozzi -Two Eagles (Box 58, Folder 28)
    - #62, Mitelli -Cartouche Detail (Box 58, Folder 29)
    - #63, Mitelli -Escutcheon Detail (Box 58, Folder 30)
    - #64, Carlo Bianconi -Escutcheon (Box 58, Folder 31)
    - #65, G.B. Bison -Arabesque Panel (Box 58, Folder 32)
    - #66, G. Barberi -Arabesque Panels (Box 58, Folder 33)
    - #67, G. Barberi -Three Decorative Panels (Box 58, Folder 34)
    - #68, Unknown Italian -Decorative Frieze (Box 58, Folder 35)
    - #69, Mitelli -Wall Tablet (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - #70, Fortunato Tesi -Wall Tablet (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - #71, Babel -Cartouche (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - #72, La Joue -Decorative Motifs (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - #73, Giovanni Guerra -Rondel with Aldobrandini Arms (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - #74, Delafosse -Portrait of Ragueneau (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - #75, Hubert -Sconce (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - #76, J.C. Delafosse -Candelabra Design (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - #77, Unknown Italian -Coach Design (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - #78, C. Ferri -Coach Design (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - #79, Mauro Oddi -Book Illustration (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - #89, G. Barberi -Church Tablet (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - #81, Oppenord -Title Page (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - #82, Mauro Gandolfi -A. Covelli Frontispiece (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - #83, Pierre Lelu -Archway with Temple of Venus and Rome (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - #84, Antonio Zucchi -Landscape and Bridge (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - #86, Tesi -Ruins Composition (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - #87, Buffagnotti -Garden Scene (Box 59, Folder 18)
    - #88, Pillemont -Calvert with Two Figures (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - #89, G.B. Bison -Architectural Fantasy (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - #90, Challe -Ruins (Box 59, Folder 21)
    - #91, T. Mossmer -Gardens Through an Arch (Box 59, Folder 22)
    - #92, Mitelli -Tromp L'oeil (Box 59, Folder 23)
    - #93, Pillement -Landscape with Goats (Box 59, Folder 24)
    - #94, G. P. Panini -Ruins and Figures (Box 59, Folder 25)
    - #95, C.J. Vernet -Italian Landscape (Box 59, Folder 26)
    - #95, Mitelli -Tromp L'eoil Wall Decoration (Box 59, Folder 27)
    - #96, Alessio de Marchis -Landscape (Box 59, Folder 28)
    - #97, Carlo Labruzzi -Landscape (Box 59, Folder 29)
    - #98, Carlo Labruzzi -View Near Civita Castellana (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - #99, Louis Belanger -Landscape (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - #100, A.L. Morel-Fatio -View Near Bomarsund (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - #101, Edward Lear -Catenia and Mt. Etna (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - #102, F. Moucheron -Landscape (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - #103, Giacinto Giganti -Naples from the Vomero (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - #104, Maxime Lalanne -Garden Scene (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - #106, Georg Friedrich Moch -Soldiers at Rest (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - #107, Unknown Italian -Marriage of the Virgin (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - #108, Fran├ºois Verdier -Surrender of a General (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - #109, E.A. Simonini -Soldiers Near a Walled City (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - #110, Francesco Simonini -Calvary Skirmish (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - #111, Francesco Simonini -A Mounted Officer (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - #112, J.A. Volaire -Four Standing Men (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - #113, Ghezzi -Procurator General (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - #114, Ghezzi -Father John the First (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - #116bdf, M. Tesi -Grotesque Heads (Box 60, Folder 17)
    - #116c, P. Panfili -Escutcheon and Grotesque Head (Box 60, Folder 18)
    - #117, Donato Creti -Three Female Figures (Box 60, Folder 19)
    - #118, Paolo Caliari -Figure Sketches (Box 60, Folder 20)
    - #119, F. Duranti -Madonna and Child (Box 60, Folder 21)
    - #120, P.A. Novelli -Female Figures (Box 60, Folder 22)
    - #121, Unknown Italian -Glorification Allegory (Box 60, Folder 23)
    - Bibiena -Stage Set (Box 60, Folder 24)
    - Bison, G.B. -Burning Brazier (Box 60, Folder 25)
    - Buffagnotti, C.A. -Imaginary Landscapes (Box 60, Folder 26)
    - Cachaud (Box 60, Folder 27)
    - Casanova, Franc -Battle Scene (Box 60, Folder 28)
    - Civoli, G. -Ceiling Cove Sketches (Box 60, Folder 29)
    - Conco, Sebastiano -Adoration of a Holy Picture (Box 60, Folder 30)
    - de la Fosse, C. -Sacrifice Scene (Box 60, Folder 31)
    - Galliari -Stage Set and Columned Hall (Box 60, Folder 32)
    - Graziani -Reliquary (Box 60, Folder 33)
    - Graziani -Over Arch Decoration (Box 60, Folder 34)
    - Jarmorini (Box 60, Folder 35)
    - Minozzi, F.I. -Elevation of Altar Wall (Box 60, Folder 36)
    - Mitelli -Cartouche, Enframement and Door Pediment (Box 60, Folder 37)
    - Mitelli -Ceiling Cove Study (Box 60, Folder 38)
    - Mitelli -Escutcheon (Box 60, Folder 39)
    - Mitelli -Left Section of a Frame (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Mitelli -Memorial Tablets (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Mitelli -Tromp L'oeils (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Mitelli follower -Tromp L'oeils (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Mitelli follower -Vault Corners (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Morland G. -Travellers (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Papini, Giordano -Venetian Scene (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Piazzetta follower -Head of a Man Looking Down (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Piazzetta follower -Head of a Man Looking Up (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Rigaud, Hyacinthe -Portrait of a Lady (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Tesi, Mauro -Welltomb (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Thibault, J.T. -Vault Decorations (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - Unknown -Heluan, Egypt (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - Unknown French -Mules at a Fountain (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Unknown Bolognese -Elevation of an Altar Screen (Box 61, Folder 15)
    - Unknown Italian -Building Under Construction (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - Unknown Italian -Baths of Caracalla (Box 61, Folder 17)
    - Unknown Italian -Book Vignette (Box 61, Folder 18)
    - Unknown Italian -3-Section Ceiling (Box 61, Folder 19)
    - Unknown Italian -Ceiling and Cove (Box 61, Folder 20)
    - Unknown Italian -Forum in Ruins (Box 61, Folder 21)
    - Unknown Italian -Seaport, Landscape with Bridge (Box 61, Folder 22)
    - Unknown Italian -Wall Tablets (Box 61, Folder 23)
    - Unknown North Italian -Martyrdom of a Saint (Box 61, Folder 24)
    - Vaccaro, F. -Landscape (Box 61, Folder 25)
    - Vernet, Carle -Caricature (Box 61, Folder 26)
    - Vincent, V. Adam -Crimean War Sketches (Box 61, Folder 27)
    - 19th Century -Melange of Tuscan Monuments (Box 61, Folder 28)
    - 19th Century (English) -Landscape (Box 61, Folder 29)
    - Album of Decorative Drawings (Box 61, Folder 30)
    - Lord Castlemaine Book (Box 61, Folder 31)
    - Kim Moll correspondence - Gorilla Sam (Box 61, Folder 32)
    - Sculpture - A.H. Huntington (Box 61, Folder 33)
  - Oppenord, Gilles-Marie, 1672-1742
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 61, Folder 34)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 61, Folder 35)
    - Chronology and Notes, undated (Box 61, Folder 36)
- Series VI: Stage Set/Theatre Drawings, 1958-1972, 1.0 Linear feet (2 boxes)
  Contains correspondence, photographs, published catalogs, drafts, notes, and promotional materials for three of Wunder's research projects that relate to stage set/theater drawings (two in conjunction with an exhibition and catalog publication).
  - The Baroque Illusion: Stage Designs, 1650-1850 from Cooper Union Museum
    An exhibition of 63 drawings from a variety of set designers of the 17th through the 19th century, assembled by the Cooper Union Museum to be circulated by the American Federation of the Arts.
    - Draft catalog descriptions, photographs of drawings, undated (Box 62, Folder 1-2)
    - Promotional materials, notes, 1958 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Oenslager Stage Set Drawings
    Wunder wrote the catalog for the exhibition,Theater Drawings from the Donald Oenslager Collection at Minneapolis Institute of Arts and helped curate the AFA circulating exhibition,Four Centuries of Theater Design: Drawings from the Collection of Donald Oenslager.
    - Correspondence, 1962-1972 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Draft catalog entries, photographs of drawings (Box 62, Folder 5-7)
    - Catalog, press releases, 1963-1965 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Notes, undated (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Stage Set Drawings
    Material relates to various stage design drawings, including many by Bibiena and Oenslager. Unclear whether the material was collected for any particular project.
    - Correspondence, 1959, 1961, 1967 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of drawings, undated (Box 63, Folder 4-7)
    - Newspaper clippings, notes, 1955, 1964, undated (Box 63, Folder 8)
- Series VII: Other Drawings, 1957-1989, 2.5 Linear feet (5 boxes)
  Contains materials regarding Wunder's various research projects involving drawings, some of which were completed in the service of creation of a catalog, exhibition, or article. Types of material include photographs, correspondence, catalogs, notes, drafts, and promotional materials. Materials are arranged alphabetically by research topic.
  - American Drawings of the Nineteenth Century from the Collection of the Cooper Union Museum
    - List of drawings, photographs of drawings, undated (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - "Castiglione Pen Drawings in the Cooper Union Museum"
    Materials regarding the article Wunder wrote for the Art Bulletin.
    - Correspondence, 1958-1963 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of drawings, catalog descriptions, circa 1960 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Galley proof, draft, circa 1960 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Notes, circa 1960 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - "The Cooper Union Museum Collection of Drawings and Prints: Its History and Its Aim"
    Wunder wrote this article for a publication by Carl Zigrosser, the former curator of Prints and Drawings at the Philadelphia Museum of Art. It was not accepted.
    - Correspondence, draft, photographs, 1961 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Cooper Union Drawings
    - Correspondence, 1956-1987 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Photographs of drawings, undated (Box 64, Folder 8-10)
    - Note cards, undated (Box 64, Folder 11)
      Contains catalog cards for Cooper Union Museum drawings. Some have a small photograph of the drawing affixed to the card.
      Located in Note Card Box 6.
  - "Decloux Collection of French Decorative Drawings"
    Catalog type article written for Art Quarterly about the Leon Decloux collection at the Cooper Union Museum.
    - Correspondence, draft, 1962 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Durcal Collection
    Material regarding drawings from the collection of the Duke of Durcal acquired by the Smithsonian National Gallery of Fine Arts.
    - Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of drawings, catalog descriptions, undated (Box 65, Folder 3-5)
    - Auction catalog (photocopy), notes, 1889, undated (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Extravagant Drawings of the 16th and 17th Centuries in the Collection of the Cooper Union Museum
    - Photographs of drawings, catalog descriptions, undated (Box 65, Folder 7-8)
    - Photographs of drawings, catalog descriptions, undated (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Extravagant Drawings of the 18th Century from the Collection of the Cooper Union Museum
    Catalog written by Wunder.
    - Correspondence, 1961-1967 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of drawings, undated (Box 66, Folder 3-4)
    - Catalog (draft), 1962 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Catalog (proof), 1962 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Galleys, 1962 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Promotional materials (reviews, press releases), 1962-1963 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Five Centuries of Drawing: The Cooper Union Centennial Exhibition
    Exhibition selected and arranged by Wunder, and circulated by the American Federation of the Arts.
    - Catalog, promotional materials, correspondence, lecture, 1959-1960 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of drawings, descriptions, undated (Box 67, Folder 2-4)
  - French Drawings
    - Correspondence, 1962, 1967, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Photographs of drawings, undated (Box 67, Folder 6-7)
    - Photographs of drawings in the Tessin Harleman Collection at the Stockholm National Museum, undated (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Holbein article
    Article written by Wunder, "Three Ornament Drawings Attributed to Holbein in the Cooper Union Museum," published in Art Quarterly.
    - Reprint, correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Kenyon Cox Drawings
    Material regarding Kenyon Cox artwork at the Cooper Union Museum.
    - Correspondence, notes, 1959-1962, undated (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Note cards, circa 1959-1962 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Metalwork
    - Correspondence, photographs, monograph, notes, 1945-1959, undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Old Master Drawings
    - Sales catalog excerpts (Bernasconi family), 1989 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - "Solimena Drawings in the Cooper Union Museum: A New Discovery and Others"
    Article written by Wunder, published in Art Quarterly.
    - Correspondence, photographs and descriptions, reprint, 1960-1961 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Travel to England and Rome
    - Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 68, Folder 6)
- Series VIII: Other Art Research, 1945-1974, 2.25 Linear feet (5 boxes)
  Contains photographs, correspondence, notes, and drafts related to research Wunder completed on various miscellaneous art topics. This research was at times in the service of an article or exhibition Wunder was working on. Materials are arranged alphabetically by research topic.
  - Benedict XIV
    - Notes, draft of essay, undated (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Benisovich, Michel material
    Contains some of the research papers of Michel Benisovich, Wunder's colleague.
    - Ghezzi, Pier Leone, 1674-1755 - notes, correspondence, essay, 1962-1963 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Taunay, Nicolas Antoine, 1755-1830 - dissertation (Box 69, Folder 3-5)
      Two copies - one bound, one loose.
    - Taunay, Nicolas Antoine, 1755-1830 - dissertation (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Taunay, Nicolas Antoine, 1755-1830 - correspondence, photographs, notes found inserted in the loose dissertation., 1956-1959, undated (Box 70, Folder 2-3)
  - Catafalques
    - Notes, undated (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Chardin, Jean Baptiste Sim├®on and Grueze, Jean Baptiste
    Wunder contributed articles to the New Catholic Encyclopedia about Chardin and Grueze.
    - Correspondence, draft, contributor agreement forms, 1964 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Chase, William Merritt
    Concerns an article Wunder intended to write about William Merritt Chase in Bruges.
    - Correspondence, photographs, primary source material, 1912, 1967-1968 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence
    - Gernsheim, Dr. Walter, 1950-1959 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Venetian paintings, 1954 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1955, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Early Renaissance
    - Photographs and correspondence regarding a Donatello relief, 1947 (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Fontana, Francesco
    Concerns an article Wunder wrote, "The Raising and Transportation of the Column of Antoninus Pius."
    - Correspondence, manuscript, photographs, notes, 1959 (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - French Sales Catalogs - 18th Century
    - Photographs of catalogs, undated (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - Joseph Harrison Jr. Collection
    Concerns an article Wunder was preparing for Art Quarterly.
    - Artist Files, 1966-1968 (Box 71, Folder 1-6)
      Includes provenance forms for each piece in the collection. In some cases photographs, notes, or correspondence accompany the forms.
    - "Art Activities of Joseph Harrison Jr." - photocopy of inventory ledger, undated (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Book -The Iron Worker and King Solomon by Joseph Harrison Jr., 1871 (Box 72, Folder 1)
      Inscribed: "Joseph Harrison Jr. to his sister Maria Oct. 24 1871" Book cover is also embossed "to my sister maria" Leather cover with clasps.
  - Japanese Prints
    Concerns an exhibition of 15 prints selected from the Cooper Union Museum and circulated by the American Federation of Arts.
    - Correspondence, promotional materials, 1962-1963 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Lafayette portrait by John Neagle
    - Photographs, notes, draft, 1963, undated (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Note cards
    - Artwork files, undated (Box 73, Folder 3)
      Arranged alphabetically by artist. Unclear what these cards pertain to.
      Located in Note Card Box 7.
  - Paschal I
    - Notes, undated (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Pio Panfili
    - Photostats of illustrations from an 18th century publication (microfilmed), 1963 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Pietro da Cortona
    - Correspondence, draft, notes, 1947, 1951, undated (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Thomas P. Rossiter
    - Biographical sketch (photocopy), 1968 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Checklist of paintings, list of contents of scrapbook (photocopies), undated (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1974 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - Silvio Valenti-Gonzaga Collection
    - Provenance forms for each painting 1-800, undated (Box 74, Folder 1-8)